<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Joel Dare</title>
    <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Joel Dare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.joeldare.com/blog/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Give Your Computer Instructions It&amp;rsquo;s easy to start giving your computer instructions. You&amp;rsquo;ve already got the tool you need; your web browser. Lets open a special window called the console.
Select the View menu, then Developer, and JavaScript Console. The menu will look similar to this.
Hello World It&amp;rsquo;s tradition to have your first program say hello to the world. Type the following into the console and press enter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Instagram Like Bot</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/simple-instagram-like-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/simple-instagram-like-bot/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple Instagram like bot written in JavaScript.
Google Chrome Extension The easiest and safest tool to use is my Magis extension for Google Chrome. Gain new followers and likes on Instagram. Magis reminds you to be active and provides keyboard shortcuts to make liking and commenting fast. Set a goal to like and comment on 10 posts an hour to significantly increase your Instagram engagement with just two minutes of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Awk on CSV Files</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/using-awk-on-csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/using-awk-on-csv-files/</guid>
      <description>You can use AWK to quickly look at a column of data in a CSV file.
In my case, the CSV files are in the following format:
&amp;quot;field1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;field2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;field3&amp;quot;  To view the 3rd field of every line, you can use the following command.
awk -F &amp;quot;\&amp;quot;*,\&amp;quot;*&amp;quot; &#39;{print $3}&#39; file.csv  As another example, take the following pipe delimited format:
field1|field2|field3  To view the 2nd field of every line, you can use the following command.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>