<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joel Dare</title>
    <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joel Dare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.joeldare.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Repeater to Memory on a Baofeng UV-5R</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/add-a-repeater-to-memory-on-a-baofeng-uv-5r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/add-a-repeater-to-memory-on-a-baofeng-uv-5r/</guid>
      <description>You must be in frequency mode (VFO) and on the A (top) line in order to customize a frequency and then save it. Do the following to switch to frequency mode and the top line.
 Press the VFO/MR button to switch to Frequency (VFO) mode. Make sure you are on the A (top) line. Press the A/B button to switch to the A line.  Once you&amp;rsquo;re in the correct mode and on the correcty line you generally do the following.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ham Memory Channels</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/my-ham-memory-channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/my-ham-memory-channels/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of my own HAM radio memory channels. The majority of these will be for repeaters near my home in Roy, UT.
   Ch Frequency PL Name Location     001 147.040 + 123.0 DCARC Repeater Antelope Island   002 146.900 - 123.0 OARC Repeater Mount Ogden   003 447.200 - 127.3 DCARC Repeater Antelope Island   004 448.600 - 123.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone Motorcycle Trip</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/yellowstone-motorcycle-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/yellowstone-motorcycle-trip/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m planning to ride my motorcycle, a small Suzuki TU250X through Yellowstone National Park. It&amp;rsquo;s a three day trip and I should put around 300 miles on the bike. It&amp;rsquo;s the longest ride I&amp;rsquo;ve done on a motorcycle and a long ride for a 250cc bike with a 240 lb rider and camping gear. This will be both my first multiple day ride and my first motorcycle camping trip. I will be traveling alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Cleaned My Central Air Coil</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-i-cleaned-my-ac-coil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-i-cleaned-my-ac-coil/</guid>
      <description>My central air unit wasn&amp;rsquo;t working very well. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I&amp;rsquo;ve been more than a little lax about changing out my furnace filters. The filters are cheap; replace them regularly to avoid having to do this type of maintenance. Most filters suggest changing them every 30 to 90 days.
My wife works as an admin in the home construction industry. She knew some people so she called a couple friends to check out the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steno Pad Idea Worksheet</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/steno-pad-idea-worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/steno-pad-idea-worksheet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked Steno Pads for writing notes. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly what it is but the smallish size, spiral bound top edge, and center column are all nice touches.
I work on a lot of business ideas. Most of them have been flops. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to flesh out the ideas a little better before I waste a lot of time building something. I&amp;rsquo;ve adapted a few suggestions from other note taking forms, planner pages, and feedback to a format I currently like for working out ideas on a Steno Pad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless BBS</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/wireless-bbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/wireless-bbs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by the nostalgia of the BBS systems of my youth and by the high cost of modern Internet service providers. By the impending loss of net neutrality in the United States and by the widespread spying of worldwide governments on their citizens and corporations on their customers.
Wireless BBS is a configuration suggestion for local operators who wish to share websites with their communities without connection costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Preact App from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/create-preact-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/create-preact-app/</guid>
      <description>I wrote these instructions after having written my previous instructions Create a React App from Scratch. The process is almost identical. The result is a much smaller app.
A basic preact application needs npm, yarn, babel, and webpack. This is a step by step guide to installing these things and setting up a minimal initial preact project.
I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you have npm and yarn already installed. Go install those if you don&amp;rsquo;t regularly use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a React App from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/create-a-react-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/create-a-react-app/</guid>
      <description>A basic react application needs npm, yarn, babel, and webpack. This is a step by step guide to installing these things and setting up a minimal initial react project.
I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you have npm and yarn already installed. Go install those if you don&amp;rsquo;t regularly use them. You can substitute npm commands for the yarn commands below, if you like. I use yarn so my instructions are tailored to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Implemented Comments on a Static Site</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/comments-on-a-static-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/comments-on-a-static-site/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using a static site generator for this blog and I was looking for a simple way to add comments without using a 3rd party tool like Disqus. I don&amp;rsquo;t want a 3rd party tracking my users and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to encumber my blog with any server backend. I want the site to be so simple that you could easily host it from your basement on a Raspberry Pi or otherwise very small computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/how-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Give Your Computer Instructions It&amp;rsquo;s easy to start giving your computer instructions. You&amp;rsquo;ve already got the tool you need; your web browser. Lets open a special window called the console.
Select the View menu, then Developer, and JavaScript Console. The menu will look similar to this.
Hello World It&amp;rsquo;s tradition to have your first program say hello to the world. Type the following into the console and press enter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Instagram Like Bot</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/simple-instagram-like-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/simple-instagram-like-bot/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple Instagram like bot written in JavaScript.
Google Chrome Extension The easiest and safest tool to use is my Magis extension for Google Chrome. Gain new followers and likes on Instagram. Magis reminds you to be active and provides keyboard shortcuts to make liking and commenting fast. Set a goal to like and comment on 10 posts an hour to significantly increase your Instagram engagement with just two minutes of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Awk on CSV Files</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/using-awk-on-csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/using-awk-on-csv-files/</guid>
      <description>You can use AWK to quickly look at a column of data in a CSV file.
In my case, the CSV files are in the following format:
&amp;quot;field1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;field2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;field3&amp;quot;  To view the 3rd field of every line, you can use the following command.
awk -F &amp;quot;\&amp;quot;*,\&amp;quot;*&amp;quot; &#39;{print $3}&#39; file.csv  As another example, take the following pipe delimited format:
field1|field2|field3  To view the 2nd field of every line, you can use the following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Post</title>
      <link>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/template-new-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.joeldare.com/blog/post/template-new-post/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>